Hello, I'm Jason Taylor. Welcome to my comprehensive course
on the Git source control system. Since this course is designed to
walk you through the basic concepts to mastery to Git,
I have several goals for this course.
First, I want to make sure you know where to go for help
on Git concepts and commands. You should understand
the core concepts in Git, including general source control principles.
You should have a very good understanding and practice
with the main commands, including common options and parameters.
You will be able to compare differences with ease;
branching and merging will become second nature as we thoroughly cover
both topics. You will become familiar with GitHub,
one of the most popular Git repository hosting services available.
In doing so, I want you to learn Git well enough that you could teach a friend or teammate.
Finally, I want you to enjoy the bonus material at the end.
Bonus content is provided to supplement the course
with alternative approaches, tips and tricks, and non-critical skills.