In order to accomplish the course goals,
the approach I'm going to take will follow this format:
first, an introduction to this course,
including the main motivation for source control and Git;
then, I will walk through, step by step, the installation of Git
on Windows, and the Mac; and the initial setup.
Once Git is installed, we will dive directly into a hands-on
quick win on command line, before going over any heavy theory.
I think theory and key concepts will be better understood
after some practical experience. After we have a better understanding
of how Git works, we'll dive back into the command line
by covering the basic commands in more detail.
Some of it will be review from the quickstart earlier,
but I will be adding much more detail, and more commands in this section.
With lots of changes in our repository, we will cover how to compare
the differences within our repository. After all of that,
we will cover a major part of Git: branching and merging.
Branching and merging are encouraged so much more
than in other version control systems, that I'm going to cover this in great detail.
Along the way, you will be exposed to GitHub,
which is the most popular Git hosting provider available.
And also, when needed, we will install and configure any tools
that are required, including a text editor and a visual compare and mergetool.
As promised, I will have tons of bonus content,
that I will keep adding on a regular basis, to keep this course fresh.
I believe the core of this course is done,
but I'm still working on many additional sections and refinements to this course.
So, I have priced this course accordingly. As a student of this course,
you will receive all updates free with your lifetime access.