So, you might be curious who I am and why I am qualified to teach this course.
Well, I'm a senior software engineer, with over 15 years of experience.
I've worked in all sizes of companies, from startups to large enterprises,
and I even do freelancing from time to time.
In my various roles, I've gravitated towards
the unofficial DevOps responsibilities,
in order to solve problems that commonly vex developers.
I have used some type of version control system for most of my career;
from CVS to Git, and several in-between.
In particular, I have trained hundreds of developers in person,
as well as thousands online, on how to use Git for source control.